<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Bite Sized Python Tips</title><link href="http://yasoob.github.io/blog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://yasoob.github.io/blog/feeds/inspiration-python.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://yasoob.github.io/blog/</id><updated>2013-08-02T18:27:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>5 quality screencasts worth watching</title><link href="http://yasoob.github.io/blog/5-quality-screencasts-worth-watching" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-08-02T18:27:00-04:00</updated><author><name>yasoob008</name></author><id>tag:yasoob.github.io/blog,2013-08-02:5-quality-screencasts-worth-watching</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello there fellas. I am back with another list of useful resources.
This time i am going to share with you 5 quality python screen casts
worth watching. Unlike ruby there are not really much quality screen
casts related to python out there. So without&lt;!--more--&gt; wasting a dime
lets continue with the list of those screen casts. So here it is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt;The first one if &lt;a href="http://pycandy.com/2013-07-04/encoding-specifiers-1"&gt;Encoding Specifiers and Magical Mode Lines&lt;/a&gt; in
python. There's a lot in it for learning. Go check it out and you won't
regret it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt;The second one is by Neck Beard Republic. This one is about
&lt;a href="https://www.neckbeardrepublic.com/screencasts/lambdas-functions"&gt;lambda functions in python&lt;/a&gt;. Neck Beard Republic have great python
screen casts but most of them are paid however they have some free
screen casts as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt;The third one is a series of screen casts by Kenneth Love. They
are related to django. The title is &lt;a href="http://gettingstartedwithdjango.com/en/lessons/"&gt;Getting Started With Django.&lt;/a&gt;
They are great. I have personally watched them. There's something for
everyone in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;/strong&gt;The fourth one is again by Neckbeard Republic. This one is a must
watch for every python programmer out there. The title of this screen
cast is [__dunder__ functions in python][]. There can be alot of
mystery involved in Python when it comes to the dunder (double
underscore) methods. This screen cast will reveal the secret behind
these function. However i have not personally watched it but it's on my
todo list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5.&lt;/strong&gt;Ah so now comes the last one. This one is again a Neckbeard
Republic production. This one is about the &lt;a&gt;super() literal in
python&lt;/a&gt;. I can see how much effort &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/myusuf3"&gt;Mahdi Yusuf&lt;/a&gt; has put into
making these screen casts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now we come to the end of another great post about 5 quality python
screen casts worth watching. However there are some other video
resources as well like &lt;a href="http://showmedo.com/videotutorials/python"&gt;Showmedo&lt;/a&gt; which i will cover in a future post.
If you are feeling adventurous then check out &lt;a href="http://freepythontips.wordpress.com/2013/08/01/10-inspirations-for-your-next-python-project/"&gt;10 inspirations for your
next python project&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://freepythontips.wordpress.com/2013/08/01/packaging-and-distributing-your-python-libraries/"&gt;Packaging and distributing your python
libraries&lt;/a&gt;. I hope you liked today's post. Do share your views in the
comments below and stay tuned for the next post.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="inspiration"></category><category term="must watch"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="quality"></category><category term="screencasts"></category><category term="worth watching"></category></entry><entry><title>10 inspirations for your next python project</title><link href="http://yasoob.github.io/blog/10-inspirations-for-your-next-python-project" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-08-01T23:27:00-04:00</updated><author><name>yasoob008</name></author><id>tag:yasoob.github.io/blog,2013-08-01:10-inspirations-for-your-next-python-project</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi there fellow coders. I know those times when we don't know what to
code. I am sure you must have experienced that time as well. Today i am
going to share with you 10 python projects that will serve as an
inspiration for your next python project. So without wasting a time
here's&lt;!--more--&gt; the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/python-imaging/Pillow"&gt;Pillow&lt;/a&gt; . Pillow is the "friendly" PIL fork by Alex Clark and
Contributors. PIL is the Python Imaging Library by Fredrik Lundh and
Contributors. Alex teaches us that if you don't like something then make
a fork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/kennethreitz/inbox.py"&gt;Inbox.py&lt;/a&gt;. This is the simplest SMTP server you'll ever see.
It's asynchronous. One instance should handle over one thousand emails
per second. Pretty impressive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/Hawstein/PyMinecraft"&gt;PyMinecraft&lt;/a&gt;. Have you ever thought of implementing the famous
minecraft game into python ? Hawstein has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/zedshaw/fuqit"&gt;fuqit&lt;/a&gt;. The latest and greatest from Zed Shaw (the writer of
learn python the hard way) , fuqit is a web framework that attempts to
make you forget everything you have learned from MVC frameworks and
focuses on simplicity. Zed Shaw teaches us one thing through this
project "Don't panic while doing something against the trend".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/cenkalti/pypi-notifier"&gt;PyPI Notifier&lt;/a&gt;. Watches your requirements.txt files and
notifies you via email when a project is updated. Although i have not
used it myself but i think this project is great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/bmaeser/vol"&gt;Vol&lt;/a&gt;. A simple project but great inspiration. vol lets you
control your mac's audio volume from the commandline. It also has
support for profiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/rg3/youtube-dl/"&gt;Youtube-dl&lt;/a&gt;. A great python project. It allows you to download
videos from various websites. It's a great project make sure that you
check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/lociii/jukebox"&gt;Jukebox&lt;/a&gt;. Ever wanted to listen to music with a larger group
of people e.g. in your office? Who decides what to play? Make your music
player democratic and give everyone the chance to promote their
favourite song. This script will relieve you from numerous fights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/cortesi/mitmproxy"&gt;Mitmproxy&lt;/a&gt;. mitmproxy is a an SSL capable
man-in-the-middle-proxy. It allows HTTP(and other) traffic to be
inspected and edited on the fly. Don’t be caught unaware by apps like
Path any more, now you can know what data you are sending and receiving
from remote servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/globocom/thumbor"&gt;Thumbor&lt;/a&gt;. It is a smart imaging service. It enables on-demand
crop, resizing and flipping of images. I haven't checked it out though
but it seems promising. Do check it out if you want a server side image
cropper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So finally we come to the end of this post. I hope you found some useful
python projects in there to serve as an inspiration. Share your views in
the comments below and tell me which project you liked the most or if
you want to read further then check out my another blog post about &lt;a href="http://freepythontips.wordpress.com/2013/07/30/20-python-libraries-you-cant-live-without/"&gt;20
python libraries you can't live without&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="inspiration"></category><category term="must watch"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="python projects"></category><category term="technology"></category><category term="top 10"></category></entry></feed>