<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Bite Sized Python Tips</title><link href="http://yasoob.github.io/blog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://yasoob.github.io/blog/feeds/inspiration-news.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://yasoob.github.io/blog/</id><updated>2013-11-15T00:13:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Recent posts by Guido Van Rossum</title><link href="http://yasoob.github.io/blog/recent-posts-by-guido-van-rossum" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-11-15T00:13:00-05:00</updated><author><name>yasoob008</name></author><id>tag:yasoob.github.io/blog,2013-11-15:recent-posts-by-guido-van-rossum</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi there friends. If you are a python programmer then there is not a
single chance that you don't know Guido. Everyone knows him in the
python community. However for those who don't know about him let me
introduce him to you. He is the creator of python and is known as BDFL.
Now a days he works at dropbox and previously&lt;!--more--&gt; he used to work
at google. In this post I am going to share some of his recent posts
with you. They are very informative and I suggest that you take a look
at them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://python-history.blogspot.ro/2013/11/story-of-none-true-false.html"&gt;The History of Python: The story of None, True and False (and an explanation of literals, keywords and builtins)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post Guido tells us about None, True and False and how they
became what they are right now in python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/115212051037621986145/posts/YTUxbXYZyfi"&gt;Why Python uses 0-based indexing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah so if you are a new programmer then you might have thought why python
as a lot of other languages uses 0-based indexing. There is a reason for
everything and so in this post Guido tells us the reason for why python
uses 0-based indexing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/83ppa5iykqmr14z/Py2v3Hackers2013.pptx"&gt;Python 2 vs. Python 3: A Restrospective&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name is self explanatory. This presentation is really useful and you
should definately go through it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/essjj4qmmtrhys4/SFMeetup2013.pdf"&gt;Guidos' SF presentation: Tulip: Async I/O for Python 3 @ SF Python Meetup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation guido tells about Tulip, Asynchronous I/O for
python 3. If you ever wanted to contribute to a core python library but
did not know what to contribute then do take a look at this as this
might be a good chance for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now let me say goodbye to you. I hope you enjoyed this article as
much as I enjoyed writing it. I will see you guys later. Don't forget to
follow me on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/yasoobkhalid"&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; and follow this blog as well. And finally stay
tuned for the next post as it will be great.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="guido"></category><category term="guido talks"></category><category term="guido van rossum"></category><category term="posts by guido van rossum"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="python BDFL"></category></entry></feed>