<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Bite Sized Python Tips</title><link href="http://yasoob.github.io/blog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://yasoob.github.io/blog/feeds/news-python.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://yasoob.github.io/blog/</id><updated>2013-11-13T22:18:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>PyDev 3.0 Released</title><link href="http://yasoob.github.io/blog/pydev-3-0-released" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-11-13T22:18:00-05:00</updated><author><name>yasoob008</name></author><id>tag:yasoob.github.io/blog,2013-11-13:pydev-3-0-released</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi there folks. Its been a long time since I posted here. That was
because my studies were giving me some problems. So no worrys because
the problems are all resolved and I am back with yet another news. So
what is PyDev ? If you have been coding python scripts with eclipse
(it's an IDE) then the chances are that you know what PyDev
is&lt;!--more--&gt;. So for those who are not familiar with pydev read on.
PyDev is a third-party plug-in for Eclipse. It is an Integrated
Development Environment used for programming in Python supporting code
refactoring, graphical debugging, code analysis and many other features.
Recently it's 3.0 version was released after a long break. Some believed
that the development for PyDev had stopped but this release has given
hope to eclipse lovers. According to the official pydev website PyDev
comes with many goodies such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Django integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code completion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code completion with auto import&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type hinting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to definition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactoring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debugger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remote debugger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tokens browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interactive console&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unittest integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code coverage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;and many others&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe it is worth to check out this project. The link to the
official website is &lt;a href="http://pydev.org/"&gt;http://pydev.org/&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.pydev.blogspot.com.br/2013/11/pydev-30.html"&gt;here is the link&lt;/a&gt; to
this release announcement . Do share your views in the comments below
and stay tuned for the next post. If you know someone who can benefit
from my post then do make sure that you tell them about this blog.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="eclipse python"></category><category term="eclipse python plugin"></category><category term="news"></category><category term="pydev"></category><category term="pydev 3.0"></category><category term="pydev eclipse"></category><category term="python"></category></entry><entry><title>Python 3.4 to be equipped with pip by default</title><link href="http://yasoob.github.io/blog/python-3-4-to-be-equipped-with-pip-by-default" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-22T21:59:00-04:00</updated><author><name>yasoob008</name></author><id>tag:yasoob.github.io/blog,2013-10-22:python-3-4-to-be-equipped-with-pip-by-default</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi there Pythonistas. A news has arrived that&lt;strong&gt;pip&lt;/strong&gt; will be available
by default with python 3.4. &lt;a href="http://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0453/"&gt;PEP 453&lt;/a&gt; which was "Explicit
bootstrapping of pip in Python installations" has been accepted. Python
3.4 which has entered into the beta phase after the release of final
alpha will have pip by default. If you are new to python then you might
be &lt;!--more--&gt;wondering what pip is ? Pip is a tool for installing and
managing Python packages. Previously easy_install has been the most
used package manager. &lt;em&gt;Easy_Install&lt;/em&gt; is a python module
(&lt;code&gt;easy_install&lt;/code&gt;) bundled with &lt;code&gt;setuptools&lt;/code&gt; that lets you automatically
download, build, install, and manage Python packages but has a lot of
weak points in front of pip. In order to use pip you first have to
install it by using &lt;em&gt;easy_install&lt;/em&gt;. Why pip is better:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The command is simpler, shorter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First-class support of virtualenv&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More commands than just &lt;code&gt;install&lt;/code&gt;, including &lt;code&gt;uninstall&lt;/code&gt;.
    &lt;code&gt;pip bundle&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;pip freeze&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;pip search&lt;/code&gt; are pretty nice as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can install from a VCS (via &lt;code&gt;-e&lt;/code&gt;), or from source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Requirements files are easy to use, clearly describes what happens
    in its process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it can not download all the dependencies, it will not install
    anything (though I don't think it rolls stuff back if an
    installation fails&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you are as much happy as I am with the acceptance of this PEP. Do
share your views in the comments below and don't forget to share this
post and follow this blog in order to get the latest news relating with
the python world.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="acceptance"></category><category term="news"></category><category term="PEP"></category><category term="pep 453"></category><category term="pip"></category><category term="python"></category></entry><entry><title>PyCharm 3.0 Community Edition</title><link href="http://yasoob.github.io/blog/pycharm-3-0-community-edition" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-22T21:43:00-04:00</updated><author><name>yasoob008</name></author><id>tag:yasoob.github.io/blog,2013-10-22:pycharm-3-0-community-edition</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The makers of the hugely popular Python IDE &lt;strong&gt;PyCharm&lt;/strong&gt; recently
announced a community edition of their Python IDE. &lt;strong&gt;JetBrains&lt;/strong&gt;
announced that they will be offering a community Edition of PyCharm
however it will have some stripped down features for example it will not
have builtin support for pyramid etc. However the&lt;!--more--&gt; news for a
Community version of PyCharm became hot in the python community recently
because PyCharm is currently the best IDE available for Python. This
community edition has been out for quite some time now and has already
been downloaded by a lot of developers. Today the Source code of this
IDE was also open sourced by JetBrains. The source code is available on
&lt;a href="https://github.com/JetBrains/intellij-community/"&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; . This IDE has a lot of cool features. Here are a few of the
features of the community version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intelligent Editor, with code completion, on-the-fly error
    highlighting, auto-fixes, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automated code refactorings and rich navigation capabilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrated debugger and unit testing support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Native VCS integrations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customizable UI and key-bindings, with VIM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;emulation available&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And much more, all available under the Apache 2 license&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you are as much excited as I am. I have already taken this IDE
for a test drive and have been fascinated by it's power. It is a one
stop solution for every python developer whether he is a system engineer
or a web developer. I hope you will take this IDE for a test drive. Do
share your experience in the comments below so that others can know
about your experience and don't forget to follow this blog if you want
to get latest news, tips, tricks and tutorials relating to python.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="best python ide"></category><category term="code writer"></category><category term="hot"></category><category term="IDE"></category><category term="new"></category><category term="pycharm"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="python ide"></category><category term="python news"></category></entry><entry><title>Python News 13 Oct 2013</title><link href="http://yasoob.github.io/blog/python-news-13-oct-2013" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-14T01:59:00-04:00</updated><author><name>yasoob008</name></author><id>tag:yasoob.github.io/blog,2013-10-14:python-news-13-oct-2013</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi folks in this post i am going to share with you news from the python
world. This is like a roundup of monthly news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Latest News&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2013/10/10/nhs_drops_oracle_for_riak/"&gt;NHS drops Oracle for Python, Riak, Redis, RabbitMQ, Tornado, Flask and more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The UK government's quest to get public services&lt;!--more--&gt; to use more
open source technologies seems to be taking hold, judging by the revamp
of the NHS's very large Spine service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://ipython.org/microsoft-donation-2013.html"&gt;Microsoft donates $100,000 to the IPython team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Microsoft donates $100,000 to the IPython team for the continued
development of IPython.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/pycharm/whatsnew/index.html"&gt;PyCharm 3.0 Community Edition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Jet Brains recently surprised the Python community by launching a
community version of it's extremely popular Python IDE. It's a must have
for a Python programmer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://pypi.python.org/pypi/pymongo/2.6.3"&gt;PyMongo 2.6.3 Released&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
MongoDB is one of the leading NoSQL Database. The PyMongo distribution
contains tools for interacting with MongoDB database from Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python Conferences:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://pycon.blogspot.ca/2013/10/announcing-keynotes-van-lindberg.html"&gt;PyCon 2014 Keynotes announced&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The keynote speakers for the largest Python Conference have been
announced. This year the keynote speakers include Van Lindberg, Jessica
McKellar, Fernando Perez, Guido Van Rossum and John Perry Barlow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.pytennessee.org/speaking/cfp/"&gt;PyTennessee Call for Papers!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you are in the Tennessee area and know python then make sure that
you do not miss this great chance to attend the PyTennnesse. Submit your
papers now. The deadline is 1st November.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Articles:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://tomforb.es/breaking-out-of-secured-python-environments"&gt;Breaking Out of Secured Python Shells&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Ever thought of hacking secure python shells ? I hope not but this guy
definitely thought about that and even accomplished. Hop over to his
website to read about his discovery. It is definitely worth a read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://cbarker.net/blog/projects/applications/cubr"&gt;Cubr!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A really cool project. This one involves the use of a mixed up Rubik's
Cube. Just bring the mixed layout of a Rubik's Cube in front of your
webcam and let this nifty application do it's trick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://wrobstory.github.io/2013/10/mapping-data-python.html"&gt;Mapping data in Python using Pandas and Vincent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This Blogpost clearly shows the power of Vincent. Do check it out if
you are into data mining and data representation. This Blogpost will
surely help you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://blog.explainmydata.com/2013/10/training-random-forests-in-python-using.html"&gt;Training Random Forests in Python using the GPU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Random Forests have emerged as a very popular learning algorithm for
tackling complex prediction problems. These guys have released GPU
Random Forest library for Python called CudaTree. Check this out if you
want to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://juliahgrace.com/intro-hardware-hacking-arduino.html"&gt;Introduction to Hardware Hacking with Arduino&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There are not a lot of post out there which explain clearly how to hack
an Arduino using Python and turning it into a useful creature. This post
is for Hardware Hackers who are a bit familiar with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.toptal.com/python/why-are-there-so-many-pythons"&gt;Why are there so many Pythons ?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This post starts from scratch and takes you step by step into the world
of different Python implementations. Read it if you have time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://blog.dbrgn.ch/2013/3/26/perceptrons-in-python/"&gt;Programming a Perceptron in Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A perceptron classifier is a simple model of a neuron. In this post the
author programs a Perceptron in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://zulko.github.io/blog/2013/09/27/read-and-write-video-frames-in-python-using-ffmpeg/"&gt;Read and Write Video Frames in Python Using FFMPEG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This article shows how easy it is to read or write video frames with
Python, by calling the external software FFMPEG through pipes. Worth the
read if you are interested in video manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting Projects:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://pypi.python.org/pypi/csscompressor"&gt;csscompressor -- A python port of YUI CSS Compressor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Port of YUI CSS Compressor to Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://cintruder.sourceforge.net/"&gt;CIntruder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Captcha Intruder is an automatic pentesting tool to bypass captchas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/crsmithdev/arrow"&gt;Arrow 0.4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Better dates &amp;amp; times for Python, now with ISO-8601 parsing and week
support!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/CamDavidsonPilon/lifelines"&gt;Lifelines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Survival analysis in Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/realgam3/pymultitor"&gt;Pymultitor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
With this algorithm you can use multiple tor threads to make multiple
requests with multiple IP addresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/kennethreitz/flask-sockets"&gt;Flask-Sockets: Easy WebSockets in Flask, by Kenneth Reitz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This guy is super nice and always contribute useful libraries. This one
is no less. Check this out if you are working with websockets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://pythonhosted.org/Whoosh/intro.html"&gt;Whoosh - a fast, pure Python search engine library.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Really a wonderful project. Whoosh is a fast, pure Python search engine
library. Whoosh is not really a search engine, it’s a programmer library
for creating a search engine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/FZambia/centrifuge"&gt;Centrifuge - real-time messaging in web applications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Simple real-time messaging in web applications.The main goal of
Centrifuge is the same as of &lt;a href="http://pusher.com/"&gt;Pusher&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://www.pubnub.com/"&gt;Pubnub&lt;/a&gt; services. The main
difference is that Centrifuge is open-source and requires installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you liked this roundup. Make sure that you share this post on
Facebook and Twitter. Stay tuned for the next post! Also do follow my
blog so that you do not miss a single post and finally comment below if
I missed something and if you think that I should do similar posts in
the future as well.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="news"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="python development"></category><category term="python news"></category><category term="python projects"></category><category term="weekly news"></category><category term="weekly newsletter"></category></entry></feed>