<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Bite Sized Python Tips</title><link href="http://yasoob.github.io/blog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://yasoob.github.io/blog/feeds/python-welcome.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://yasoob.github.io/blog/</id><updated>2013-07-31T14:19:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>10 python blogs worth following</title><link href="http://yasoob.github.io/blog/10-python-blogs-worth-following" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-07-31T14:19:00-04:00</updated><author><name>yasoob008</name></author><id>tag:yasoob.github.io/blog,2013-07-31:10-python-blogs-worth-following</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi there fellow programmers. I remember those days when i started
learning python. I was always eager to find new blogs about python but
found just a handful of them. This is one of the reason i started this
blog.&lt;!--more--&gt; To spread my knowledge about python to other fellow
coders. Today i am going to try to provide you 10 links to different
python blogs that are worth following. By that i mean they are regularly
updated and have useful info. So here's the list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; The first one is &lt;a href="http://planet.python.org/"&gt;Planet python&lt;/a&gt; undoubtedly one of the most
famous python blogs out there. Go check it out. I hope you will find it
helpful. It was last updated today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; The second blog is &lt;a href="http://lucumr.pocoo.org/"&gt;lucumr&lt;/a&gt;. The home of the developer of flask
(a python micro web framework).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; The third blog is &lt;a href="http://love-python.blogspot.com/"&gt;love-python&lt;/a&gt;. I don't know how i stumbled
over it but i really like this blog as it has a lot of useful info and
code snippets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;/strong&gt; The fourth blog is of&lt;a href="http://doughellmann.com/"&gt;Doug Hellmann&lt;/a&gt;. He is the one behind
PYMOTW (Python Module Of The Week). This blog covers a lot of python
libraries. If you are searching for some new useful python libraries
then go check this out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5.&lt;/strong&gt; The next blog is &lt;a href="http://sayspy.blogspot.com/"&gt;Coder Who Says Py&lt;/a&gt;. It's a nice blog.
Although it's not regularly updated but still you will find some helpful
info in there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6.&lt;/strong&gt; The sixth blog is &lt;a href="http://effbot.org/"&gt;effbot&lt;/a&gt;. Full of helpful info, code snippets
and everything else you can expect from a python blog. Go check it out
before it's too late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7.&lt;/strong&gt; The seventh blog is of the writer of "Two Scoops Of Django". It
is &lt;a href="http://pydanny.com/"&gt;pydanny&lt;/a&gt;. This is mainly about django but still a lot can be
learned from this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8.&lt;/strong&gt; The next &lt;a href="http://inventwithpython.com/blog/"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; is of Al Sweigat. He is the writer of numerous
python books including his latest book "Hacking Secret Ciphers With
Python".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9.&lt;/strong&gt; The ninth blog is &lt;a href="http://www.freepythontips.wordpress.com"&gt;this blog&lt;/a&gt; on which you currently are. This
is your all in one guide to python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10.&lt;/strong&gt; The last blog is one of the most useful blog which got me up to
speed with python. It is called &lt;a href="http://www.blog.pythonlibrary.org/"&gt;Mouse Vs Python&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you liked today's post and i am sure i helped you out of your
frustration of finding good python blogs. Do share your views in the
comments below and if you think that i have missed a blog then put it in
the comments as well.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="best"></category><category term="blogs"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="top 10"></category><category term="worth following"></category></entry></feed>